<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./FoodChainLab_transp.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.8 http://knime.org/node/v2.8.xsd">
	<name>Tracing</name>

	<shortDescription>
      	Provides forward and backward tracing. 
    </shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			This node can visualize a supply chain. The three input ports expect a station table, an
			delivery table and a delivery relations table. These tables are provided by the Supply Chain
			Analyzer. Tracing can be performed by setting the following four properties for stations and
			deliveries: "Case Weight", "Cross Contamination", "Kill Contamination" and "Observed". Each of
			the properties can be set in the respective tab. Based on these properties the following values
			are computed: "Score", "Normalized Score", "Forward", "Backward".
		</intro>

		<tab name="Station Properties">
			<option name="Weight">
				Weights for stations. The computed scores are based on these weights.
			</option>
			<option name="Cross Contamination">
				Set cross contamination for stations. That means all incoming deliveries can
				contaminate all outgoing deliveries (see "Enforce Temporal Order").
			</option>
			<option name="Kill Contamination">
				Set kill contamination for stations. That means contaminations from incoming
				deliveries are killed. Outgoing deliveries are therefore uncontaminated.
			</option>
			<option name="Observed">
				For all stations/deliveries that can reached by forward/backward tracing from
				stations selected here, the "Forward"/"Backward" property is set to true.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Delivery Properties">
			<option name="Weight">
				Weights for deliveries. The computed scores are based on these weights.
			</option>
			<option name="Cross Contamination">
				Set cross contamination for deliveries. Similar to "Station Cross
				Contamination", but unselected (no cross contamination) incoming deliveries and outgoing
				deliveries, that are only connected to unselected incoming deliveries, are excluded from the
				cross contamination.
			</option>
			<option name="Kill Contamination">
				Set kill contamination for deliveries. That means contaminations from these
				deliveries are killed. Connected outgoing deliveries are therefore uncontaminated.
			</option>
			<option name="Observed">
				For all stations/deliveries that can reached by forward/backward tracing from
				deliveries selected here, the "Forward"/"Backward" is set to true.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Options">
			<option name="Enforce Temporal Order">
				If checked, the delivery date is used for cross contamination. That means a
				delivery can only contaminate deliveries with a later date.
			</option>
			<option name="Filter">
				Allows to apply a filter to all stations/deliveries. Only filtered
				stations/deliveries are shown in the table.
			</option>
			<option name="Clear">
				Clears the input in the table. True/false values are set to false and numbers
				are set to zero.
			</option>
			<option name="Set All">
				Sets all the values for all filtered stations/deliveries to "true"/"specfied
				value".
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Stations">
			Table with Station data. Is provided by first out port of Supply
			Chain Reader.
		</inPort>
		<inPort index="1" name="Deliveries">
			Table with Delivery data. Is provided by second out port of Supply
			Chain Reader.
		</inPort>
		<inPort index="2" name="Delivery Relations">
			Model that contains the relations between deliveries. Is provided by
			third out port of Supply Chain Reader.
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Stations Tracing">
			Table with Station data and tracing results.
		</outPort>
		<outPort index="1" name="Deliveries Tracing">
			Table with Delivery data and tracing results.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
