<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./fitting.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.10"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
	<name>Differential Function Fitting</name>

	<shortDescription>	
		Fits data to a scalar function consisting of first order differential equations.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			Fits data to a scalar function consisting of first order differential equations. The table
			from the second input port must contain "time/dependent-variable" pairs. The table from the third
			input port must contain "time/condition" tuples.
		</intro>

		<option name="Fit All At Once">
			If checked, the same values for differential equation parameters are used for
			all data sets. Otherwise each data set is fitted separately.
		</option>
		<option name="Use Different Value for *_0">
			If checked, for each data set a different value for *_0 is computed. That
			means, that the respective differential equation has a different start value for each data set.
			Otherwise all data sets use the same start value.
		</option>
		<option name="Expert Settings">
			When checked, all the following options can be set/changed. Otherwise default
			parameters are used.
		</option>
		<option name="Integration Step Size">
			The Runge–Kutta method is used for integrating the differential equations.
			This options specifies the step size to use.
		</option>
		<option name="Interpolation Function">
			The condition values are provided to node for specific times. The fitting
			algorithm must interpolate between these values. This option specifies the interpolation function
			to use.
		</option>
		<option name="Maximum Evaluations to Find Start Values">
			Before the optimization algorithm is executed, multiple combinations of start
			values are evaluated to find the combinations with the lowest errors. This option specifies the
			maximum number of start value combinations, that are evaluated evaluated.
		</option>
		<option name="Maximum Executions of Optimization Algorithm">
			The optimization algorithm is executed with start value combinations, that
			have the lowest errors. This option specifies the maximum of start value combinations, with which
			the algorithm is executed.
		</option>
		<option name="Stop When Optimization Successful">
			If checked, the first successful result of the optimization algorithm is used
			as the result of this node and the execution is stopped. Otherwise the execution continues to
			find better results.
		</option>
		<option name="Maximum Iterations in each run of Optimization Algorithm">
			This option specifies the maximum of iterations of the optimization algorithm
			for each start value combination.
		</option>
		<option name="Specific Start Values for Fitting Procedure">
			Here the user can specify boundaries for the start value of each parameter.
		</option>
		<option name="Enforce start values as limits">
			If checked, the optimization algorithm only return results, where the
			parameter values are in the specified boundaries.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="In-Port name">
			0
		</inPort>
		<inPort index="1" name="In-Port name">
			1
		</inPort>
		<inPort index="2" name="In-Port name">
			2
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Out-Port name">
			0
		</outPort>
		<outPort index="1" name="Out-Port name">
			1
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
