<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./fitting.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.10"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
	<name>Function Fitting</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Fits data to a simple scalar function.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			Fits data to a simple scalar function.
		</intro>

		<option name="Level of Detection">
			When enabled regression with the independent variable subject to the specified
			detection limit is performed (NIE, Lei, et al. Linear regression with an independent variable
			subject to a detection limit. Epidemiology (Cambridge, Mass.), 2010, 21. Jg., Nr. Suppl 4, S.
			S17).
		</option>
		<option name="Expert Settings">
			When checked, all the following options can be set/changed. Otherwise default
			parameters are used.
		</option>
		<option name="Maximum Evaluations to Find Start Values">
			Before the optimization algorithm is executed, multiple combinations of start
			values are evaluated to find the combinations with the lowest errors. This option specifies the
			maximum number of start value combinations, that are evaluated evaluated.
		</option>
		<option name="Maximum Executions of Optimization Algorithm">
			The optimization algorithm is executed with start value combinations, that
			have the lowest errors. This option specifies the maximum of start value combinations, with which
			the algorithm is executed.
		</option>
		<option name="Stop When Optimization Successful">
			If checked, the first successful result of the optimization algorithm is used
			as the result of this node and the execution is stopped. Otherwise the execution continues to
			find better results.
		</option>
		<option name="Maximum Iterations in each run of Optimization Algorithm">
			This option specifies the maximum of iterations of the optimization algorithm
			for each start value combination.
		</option>
		<option name="Specific Start Values for Fitting Procedure">
			Here the user can specify boundaries for the start value of each parameter.
		</option>
		<option name="Enforce start values as limits">
			If checked, the optimization algorithm only return results, where the
			parameter values are in the specified boundaries.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Function">
			Simple scalar function, that is fitted to the data.
		</inPort>
		<inPort index="1" name="Data">
			Data, to which the function is fitted.
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Parameter Values">
			Parameter value and some quality measures.
		</outPort>
		<outPort index="1" name="Covariance Matrix">
			Covariance matrix of the parameters.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
