<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./fitting.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.10"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
	<name>Interactive Differential Function Fitting</name>

	<shortDescription>
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			Insert long description here...
		</intro>

		<tab name="Display Options">
			<option name="Show Legend">
				If checked, a legend is shown below the chart.
			</option>
			<option name="Draw Lines">
				If checked, the data points in the chart are connected by lines.
			</option>
			<option name="Resolution">
				Number of points, that are evaluated for each function to draw the graph.
				This also controls the integration step size for drawing the graph.
			</option>
			<option name="Interpolation Function">
				Condition values are just provided for specific times. The integration
				algorithm must interpolate between these values. This option specifies the interpolation
				function to use.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Range">
			<option name="Set Minimum to Zero">
				If checked, the lower left corner of the chart is set to (0/0).
			</option>
			<option name="Set Manual Range">
				If checked, the ranges of the chart can be manually set via "Min X", "Max X",
				"Min Y", "Max Y". Otherwise the ranges are set automatically.
			</option>
			<option name="Min X">
				Minimum value of x-Axis.
			</option>
			<option name="Max X">
				Maximum value of x-Axis.
			</option>
			<option name="Min Y">
				Minimum value of y-Axis.
			</option>
			<option name="Max Y">
				Maximum value of y-Axis.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Variables">
			<option name="X">
				Variable for the x-Axis.
			</option>
			<option name="Y">
				Variable for the y-Axis.
			</option>
			<option name="X Transform">
				Optional transformation of the x-Axis variable.
			</option>
			<option name="Y Transform">
				Optional transformation of the y-Axis variable.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Parameter Values">
			<option name="Value Slider">
				Slider for setting the parameter's start value used in the optimization
				algorithm. The slider is only enabled if limits have been set.
			</option>
			<option name="Value Field">
				Field for setting the parameter's start value used in the optimization
				algorithm.
			</option>
			<option name="Set Limits">
				Limits for the parameter's start value. These limits can be enforced in the
				optimization algorithm. And when limits are set, the value slider is enabled.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Fitting">
			<option name="Enforce Limits">
				If checked, the optimization algorithm only return results, where the
				parameter values are in the specified boundaries.
			</option>
			<option name="Maximal Iterations in each run of Optimization Algorithm">
				This option specifies the maximum of iterations of the optimization algorithm
				for each start value combination.
			</option>
			<option name="Fit All At Once">
				If checked, the same values for differential equation parameters are used for
				all data sets. Otherwise each data set is fitted separately.
			</option>
			<option name="Use Different Value for *_0">
				If checked, for each data set a different value for *_0 is computed. That
				means, that the respective differential equation has a different start value for each data set.
				Otherwise all data sets use the same start value.
			</option>
			<option name="Integration Step Size">
				The Runge–Kutta method is used for integrating the differential equations.
				This options specifies the step size to use during the fitting.
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Function">
			Scalar function consisting of first order differential equations,
			that is fitted to the data.
		</inPort>
		<inPort index="1" name="Data">
			Dependent Variable Data, to which the function is fitted.
		</inPort>
		<inPort index="2" name="Conditions">
			Conditional Variable Data, to which the function is fitted.
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Parameter Values">
			Parameter values and some quality measures.
		</outPort>
		<outPort index="1" name="Covariance Matrix">
			Covariance matrix of the parameters.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
