<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./FoodChainLab.png" type="Visualizer" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.10"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
	<name>Tracing View</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Provides visualization of supply chains and allows forward and backward tracing.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			This node can visualize a supply chain. The three mandatory input ports expect a station
			table, an delivery table and a delivery relations table. These tables are provided by the Supply
			Chain Analyzer. Tracing can be performed by setting the following four properties for stations
			and deliveries: "Case Weight", "Cross Contamination", "Kill Contamination" and "Observed". You
			can change the property values by double clicking on a station/delivery or by using
			"Station/Delivery Selection -> Show Properties" from the context menu. Based on these properties
			the following values are computed: "Score", "Normalized Score", "Positive Score", "Negative
			Score", "Forward", "Backward". The results of the tracing or any other data from input tables can
			be visualized by using highlighting (as explained below).
		</intro>

		<tab name="Station Properties">
			<option name="Weight">
				Weights for stations. The computed scores are based on these weights.
			</option>
			<option name="Cross Contamination">
				Set cross contamination for stations. That means all incoming deliveries can
				contaminate all outgoing deliveries (see "Enforce Temporal Order").
			</option>
			<option name="Kill Contamination">
				Set kill contamination for stations. That means contaminations from incoming
				deliveries are killed and do not spread to outgoing deliveries.
			</option>
			<option name="Observed">
				For all stations/deliveries that can reached by forward/backward tracing from
				stations selected here, the "Forward"/"Backward" property is set to true.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Delivery Properties">
			<option name="Weight">
				Weights for deliveries. The computed scores are based on these weights.
			</option>
			<option name="Cross Contamination">
				Set cross contamination for deliveries. Similar to "Station Cross
				Contamination", but unselected (no cross contamination) incoming deliveries and outgoing
				deliveries, that are only connected to unselected incoming deliveries, are excluded from the
				cross contamination.
			</option>
			<option name="Kill Contamination">
				Set kill contamination for deliveries. That means contaminations from these
				deliveries are killed and do not spread to outgoing deliveries.
			</option>
			<option name="Observed">
				For all stations/deliveries that can reached by forward/backward tracing from
				deliveries selected here, the "Forward"/"Backward" is set to true.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Upper Options Bar">
			<option name="Undo">
				Undo the last change.
			</option>
			<option name="Redo">
				Redo the last undone change.
			</option>
			<option name="Reset Weights">
				Resets the "Weight" property for all stations and deliveries to the input
				values.
			</option>
			<option name="Reset Cross Contamination">
				Resets the "Cross Contamination" property for all stations and deliveries to
				the input values.
			</option>
			<option name="Reset Observed">
				Resets the "Observed" property for all stations and deliveries to the input
				values.
			</option>
			<option name="Export As Svg">
				When checked a svg graphic instead of a png is put in the ouput port.
			</option>
			<option name="Switch to GIS/Graph">
				This button can be used to switch between the usual graph view and a
				geographical view. Is only enabled if latitude and longitude for stations are provided in
				columns "GeocodingLatitude" and "GeocodingLongitude".
			</option>
			<option name="GIS Type">
				Here the use can choose between different GIS visualizations. If a shape
				table is provided to the optional input port, the type "Shapefile" is also available. All types
				other types than "Shapefile" require an internet connection, since data downloaded from
				OpenStreetMap, ...
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Date Slider">
			<option name="Omit Deliveries without Date">
				If checked, all deliveries without a date are not shown.
			</option>
			<option name="Show Deliveries until">
				Only deliveries whose date is before the date specified here are shown.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Options Bar">
			<option name="Editing Mode">
				Current editing mode. If "Transforming" is selected the user can move the
				graph by using the mouse. In "Picking" mode the user can select and unselect stations and
				deliveries.
			</option>
			<option name="Show Legend">
				If checked, a legend with all highlight conditions, which have "Show in
				Legend" activated, is display in the lower left corner of the canvas.
			</option>
			<option name="Join Deliveries">
				If checked, deliveries with the same source and target are joined.
			</option>
			<option name="Arrow in Middle">
				If checked, arrows are drawn in the middle of each delivery.
			</option>
			<option name="Skip Unconnected Stations">
				If checked, stations without any connected deliveries are not shown.
			</option>
			<option name="Font">
				Font Size and type (plain or bold) can be specified here. This font is used
				for station/delivery labels and in the legend.
			</option>
			<option name="Station Size">
				Min/Max diameter of the stations. Min value is used, when no "Value
				Condition" or "Logical Value Condition" is defined for stations. Otherwise the station sizes are
				between min and max.
			</option>
			<option name="Delivery Thickness">
				Min/Max thickness of the deliveries. Min value is used, when no "Value
				Condition" or "Logical Value Condition" is defined for deliveries. Otherwise the delivery
				thicknesses are between min and max.
			</option>
			<option name="Avoid Overlay">
				If checked, geographical stations that occlude each other are moved so that
				the user can see each station.
			</option>
			<option name="Label">
				Small Label, that is displayed in the upper right corner of the graph image.
			</option>
			<option name="Show Deliveries in Meta Station">
				If checked, deliveries from a meta station to itself are shown.
			</option>
			<option name="Border Alpha">
				Alpha value used to draw the geographical borders.
			</option>
			<option name="Enforce Temporal Order">
				If checked, the delivery date is used for cross contamination. That means a
				delivery can only contaminate deliveries with a later date.
			</option>
			<option name="Show Cross Contaminated Deliveries">
				If checked, all invisible deliveries, that can be reached from the visible
				deliveries only via the cross contamination specified by the user, are made visible.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Context Menu">
			<option name="Reset Layout">
				Resets translation and scale to default.
			</option>
			<option name="Save As ...">
				The image as can be saved as a PNG- or SVG-file.
			</option>
			<option name="Apply Layout">
				Several graph layout algorithms (e.g. Fruchterman-Reingold) can be applied
				here. The algorithms are applied to the selected stations and to all stations if no stations are
				selected.
			</option>
			<option name="Station Selection -> Show Properties">
				Shows the properties of all selected stations.
			</option>
			<option name="Station Selection -> Clear">
				Clears station selection.
			</option>
			<option name="Station Selection -> Highlight Selected">
				Opens a dialog to help the user highlight all selected stations.
			</option>
			<option name="Station Selection -> Select Connections">
				Selects all deliveries, whose source and target stations
				are already selected.
			</option>
			<option name="Station Selection -> Select Incoming">
				Selects all deliveries, whose target stations are already selected.
			</option>
			<option name="Station Selection -> Select Outgoing">
				Selects all deliveries, whose source stations are already selected.
			</option>
			<option name="Station Selection -> Collapse To Meta Station">
				Collapses all selected stations into one new Meta Station.
			</option>
			<option name="Station Selection -> Expand From Meta Station">
				Expands each selected Meta Station to its original stations.
			</option>
			<option name="Station Selection -> Show Uncollapsed Properties">
				Shows the properties of all stations that were collapsed to the selected meta
				stations and all selected stations that are not meta stations.
			</option>
			<option name="Delivery Selection -> Show Properties">
				Shows the properties of all selected deliveries.
			</option>
			<option name="Delivery Selection -> Show Unjoined Properties">
				Shows the properties of all deliveries that were joined to the selected
				deliveries.
			</option>
			<option name="Delivery Selection -> Clear">
				Clears delivery selection.
			</option>
			<option name="Delivery Selection -> Highlight Selected">
				Opens a dialog to help the user highlight all selected deliveries.
			</option>
			<option name="Station Highlighting -> Edit">
				Opens a dialog to add, remove and edit Highlight Conditions for stations.
			</option>
			<option name="Station Highlighting -> Clear">
				Removes all Highlight Conditions for stations.
			</option>
			<option name="Station Highlighting -> Select Highlighted">
				All stations that have non zero values for the specified Highlight Condition
				will be selected.
			</option>
			<option name="Station Highlighting -> Add Category Highlighting">
				Automatically creates Station Highlight Conditions for all categories of
				parameter.
			</option>
			<option name="Delivery Highlighting -> Edit">
				Opens a dialog to add, remove and edit Highlight Conditions for deliveries.
			</option>
			<option name="Delivery Highlighting -> Clear">
				Removes all Highlight Conditions for deliveries.
			</option>
			<option name="Delivery Highlighting -> Select Highlighted">
				All deliveries that have non zero values for the specified Highlight
				Condition
				will be selected.
			</option>
			<option name="Delivery Highlighting -> Add Category Highlighting">
				Automatically creates Delivery Highlight Conditions for all categories of
				parameter.
			</option>
			<option name="Set Selected Stations">
				Opens a dialog to select stations based on a logical condition.
			</option>
			<option name="Set Selected Deliveries">
				Opens a dialog to select deliveries based on a logical condition.
			</option>
			<option name="Collapse by Property">
				Opens a dialog to collapse all stations (visible and invisible) to meta
				stations based on a certain property. That means all stations with the same property value will
				be collapsed to the same meta station.
			</option>
			<option name="Clear Collapsed Stations">
				Expands all meta stations.
			</option>
			<option name="Set default Highlighting">
				Default highlight conditions for stations and deliveries are automatically
				generated.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Highlight Condition List Dialog">
			<option name="">
				This dialog lets you manage the Highlight Conditions, either for stations or
				deliveries. To edit a Condition double click on it.
			</option>
			<option name="Add">
				Adds a new Highlight Condition to the list.
			</option>
			<option name="Remove">
				Removes the selected Highlight Condition from the list.
			</option>
			<option name="Prioritize Colors">
				If selected, the color of each condition overwrites all colors of conditions
				below it. Otherwise the colors are mixed.
			</option>
			<option name="Up">
				Moves the selected condition up.
			</option>
			<option name="Down">
				Moves the selected condition down.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Highlight Condition Dialog">
			<option name="Type">
				Type of the condition: "Logical Condition", "Value Condition" or "Logical
				Value Condition". Types are explained in the sections below.
			</option>
			<option name="Name">
				Name of the condition. The name is used in the "Highlight Condition List
				Dialog" and in the legend.
			</option>
			<option name="Show in Legend">
				If selected the condition will be shown in the legend.
			</option>
			<option name="Color">
				Color of the highlighted elements. For a logical conditions all true elements
				are painted. For a value condition all elements with values > 0 are painted (the higher the
				value the higher alpha value used for painting).
			</option>
			<option name="Invisible">
				If selected all true elements and elements with values > 0 are made
				invisible.
			</option>
			<option name="Adjust Thickness">
				If selected the size/thickness of the station/delivery will be adjusted based
				on the
				value of the station/delivery.
			</option>
			<option name="Label">
				Property, that should be used as a label for all true elements and elements
				with values > 0.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Logical Condition">
			<option name="">
				A logical condition is an And/Or conjunction of logical expressions like
				"City == Berlin" or "Inhabitants > 10". It can only be true or false.
			</option>
			<option name="And/Or">
				When a logical condition consists of multiple expressions, And/Or
				conjunctions between these expressions must be specified. "And"-conjunctions will be evaluated
				before "Or"-conjunctions.
			</option>
			<option name="Property">
				Property of the logical expression. Is compared to "Value".
			</option>
			<option name="Operation">
				Type of the logical expression.
			</option>
			<option name="Value">
				Value of the logical expression. Is compared to "Property".
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Value Condition">
			<option name="">
				A value condition uses numerical properties, for example "Log value of
				Inhabitants".
			</option>
			<option name="Property">
				Property of the value condition.
			</option>
			<option name="Value Type">
				Type of the value condition. If "Log Value" is used, the logarithmic function
				with base 10 is applied to all property values, before visualizing. For "Value" no function is
				applied.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Logical Value Condition">
			<option name="">
				A logical value condition is a value condition that is only applied to
				elements, for which the logical condition is true.
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Stations">
			Table with Station data. Is provided by first out port of Supply
			Chain Reader.
		</inPort>
		<inPort index="1" name="Deliveries">
			Table with Delivery data. Is provided by second out port of Supply
			Chain Reader.
		</inPort>
		<inPort index="2" name="Delivery Relations">
			Model that contains the relations between deliveries. Is provided by
			third out port of Supply Chain Reader.
		</inPort>
		<inPort index="3" name="Shape Table">
			Optional Table with geographical shape column.
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Stations">
			Table with Station data. Contains meta stations instead of
			stations contained in meta stations.
		</outPort>
		<outPort index="1" name="Deliveries">
			Table with Delivery data. Does not contain joined deliveries.
		</outPort>
		<outPort index="2" name="Graph Image">
			Image of the Graph.
		</outPort>
		<outPort index="3" name="GIS Image">
			Geographical image of the Graph.
		</outPort>
		<outPort index="4" name="Combined Image">
			Graph and GIS image combined.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
