<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./FoodChainLab.png" type="Visualizer" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.8 http://knime.org/node/v2.8.xsd">
	<name>GIS-Graph View</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Provides geographic and network visualization of locations with latitude and
		longitude.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>
				This node can visualize a graph of locations with different layouts and in a geographical map.
				The geographical map is read from the table in the first port, that has to contains a column
				with shapes. Additionally a node table in the second port, which contains the IDs, latitudes and
				longitudes of the locations, and an edge table in the third port, that specifies how the
				locations are connected, are needed as input. Any data in the node or edge table can be used for
				highlighting (as explained below).
			</p>
			<p>
				Two views of the graph are available, one showing the graph's structure and the other one its
				geographical representation. These views are synchronized. Whenever the user selects a node or
				edge in one view, its representation in the other view is automatically selected.
			</p>
		</intro>

		<tab name="Upper Options Bar">
			<option name="Export As Svg">
				When checked a svg graphic instead of a png is put in the ouput port.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Options Bar">
			<option name="Editing Mode">
				Current editing mode. If "Transforming" is selected the user can move the
				graph by using the mouse. In "Picking" mode the user can select and unselect nodes and edges.
			</option>
			<option name="Show Legend">
				If checked, a legend with all highlight conditions, which have "Show in
				Legend" activated, is display in the lower left corner of the canvas.
			</option>
			<option name="Font">
				Font Size and type (plain or bold) can be specified here. This font is used
				for node/edge labels and in the legend.
			</option>
			<option name="Join Edges">
				If checked, edges with the same source and target are joined.
			</option>
			<option name="Skip Edgeless Nodes">
				If checked, nodes without any connected edges are not shown.
			</option>
			<option name="Node Size">
				Diameter of the nodes.
			</option>
			<option name="Border Alpha">
				Alpha value used to draw the geographical borders.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Context Menu">
			<option name="Reset Layout">
				Resets translation and scale to default.
			</option>
			<option name="Save As ...">
				The image as can be saved as a PNG- or SVG-file.
			</option>
			<option name="Apply Layout">
				Several graph layout algorithms (e.g. Fruchterman-Reingold) can be applied
				here. The algorithms are applied to the selected nodes and to all nodes if no nodes are
				selected.
			</option>
			<option name="Node Selection -> Show Properties">
				Shows the properties of all selected nodes.
			</option>
			<option name="Node Selection -> Clear">
				Clears node selection.
			</option>
			<option name="Node Selection -> Highlight Selected">
				Opens a dialog to help the user highlight all selected nodes.
			</option>
			<option name="Node Selection -> Select Connections">
				Selects all edges, whose source and target nodes
				are already selected.
			</option>
			<option name="Node Selection -> Select Incoming">
				Selects all edges, whose target nodes are already selected.
			</option>
			<option name="Node Selection -> Select Outgoing">
				Selects all edges, whose source nodes are already selected.
			</option>
			<option name="Edge Selection -> Show Properties">
				Shows the properties of all selected edges.
			</option>
			<option name="Edge Selection -> Show Unjoined Properties">
				Shows the properties of all edges that were joined to the selected edges.
			</option>
			<option name="Edge Selection -> Clear">
				Clears edge selection.
			</option>
			<option name="Edge Selection -> Highlight Selected">
				Opens a dialog to help the user highlight all selected edges.
			</option>
			<option name="Node Highlighting -> Edit">
				Opens a dialog to add, remove and edit Highlight Conditions for nodes.
			</option>
			<option name="Node Highlighting -> Clear">
				Removes all Highlight Conditions for nodes.
			</option>
			<option name="Node Highlighting -> Select Highlighted">
				All nodes that have non zero values for the specified Highlight Condition
				will be selected.
			</option>
			<option name="Edge Highlighting -> Edit">
				Opens a dialog to add, remove and edit Highlight Conditions for edges.
			</option>
			<option name="Edge Highlighting -> Clear">
				Removes all Highlight Conditions for edges.
			</option>
			<option name="Edge Highlighting -> Select Highlighted">
				All edge that have non zero values for the specified Highlight Condition will
				be selected.
			</option>
			<option name="Select Nodes">
				Opens a dialog to select nodes based on a logical condition.
			</option>
			<option name="Select Edges">
				Opens a dialog to select edges based on a logical condition.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Highlight Condition List Dialog">
			<option name="">
				This dialog lets you manage the Highlight Conditions, either for nodes or
				edges. To edit a Condition double click on it.
			</option>
			<option name="Add">
				Adds a new Highlight Condition to the list.
			</option>
			<option name="Remove">
				Removes the selected Highlight Condition from the list.
			</option>
			<option name="Prioritize Colors">
				If selected, the color of each condition overwrites all colors of conditions
				below it. Otherwise the colors are mixed.
			</option>
			<option name="Up">
				Moves the selected condition up.
			</option>
			<option name="Down">
				Moves the selected condition down.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Highlight Condition Dialog">
			<option name="Type">
				Type of the condition: "Logical Condition", "Value Condition" or "Logical
				Value Condition". Types are explained in the sections below.
			</option>
			<option name="Name">
				Name of the condition. The name is used in the "Highlight Condition List
				Dialog" and in the legend.
			</option>
			<option name="Show in Legend">
				If selected the condition will be shown in the legend.
			</option>
			<option name="Color">
				Color of the highlighted elements. For a logical conditions all true elements
				are painted. For a value condition all elements with values > 0 are painted (the higher the
				value the higher alpha value used for painting).
			</option>
			<option name="Invisible">
				If selected all true elements and elements with values > 0 are made
				invisible.
			</option>
			<option name="Adjust Thickness">
				If selected the size/thickness of the node/edge will be adjusted based on the
				value of the node/edge.
			</option>
			<option name="Label">
				Property, that should be used as a label for all true elements and elements
				with values > 0.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Logical Condition">
			<option name="">
				A logical condition is an And/Or conjunction of logical expressions like
				"City == Berlin" or "Inhabitants > 10". It can only be true or false.
			</option>
			<option name="And/Or">
				When a logical condition consists of multiple expressions, And/Or
				conjunctions between these expressions must be specified. "And"-conjunctions will be evaluated
				before "Or"-conjunctions.
			</option>
			<option name="Property">
				Property of the logical expression. Is compared to "Value".
			</option>
			<option name="Operation">
				Type of the logical expression.
			</option>
			<option name="Value">
				Value of the logical expression. Is compared to "Property".
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Value Condition">
			<option name="">
				A value condition uses numerical properties, for example "Log value of
				Inhabitants".
			</option>
			<option name="Property">
				Property of the value condition.
			</option>
			<option name="Value Type">
				Type of the value condition. If "Log Value" is used, the logarithmic function
				with base 10 is applied to all property values, before visualizing. For "Value" no function is
				applied.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Logical Value Condition">
			<option name="">
				A logical value condition is a value condition that is only applied to
				elements, for which the logical condition is true.
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Shape Table">
			Table with shape column.
		</inPort>
		<inPort index="1" name="Node Table">
			Table with node data.
		</inPort>
		<inPort index="2" name="Edge Table">
			Table with edge data.
		</inPort>
		<inPort index="3" name="Settings">
			Optional port with settings.
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Graph Image">
			Image of the Graph.
		</outPort>
		<outPort index="1" name="Geographical Image">
			Geographical Image of the Graph.
		</outPort>
		<outPort index="2" name="Settings">
			Settings Output.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
